austintexas.gov 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy | AustinTexas.gov - The Official Website of the City of Austin

This policy is to inform visitors to the austintexas.gov Web site of its data gathering methods and use of such data. Austintexas.gov collects many types of data throughout its Web site and the degree to which this data is used will be specified below. The City of Austin may change this policy at any time at its sole discretion and without notice.

#### HIPPA Privacy Practices

The Austin/Travis County Health and Human Services Department will comply with all federal and state laws that pertain to any aspect of the clinical practices or business procedures of the Department. In particular, privacy and security rules relating to the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA), along with related state laws, are integral to matters of privacy, medical records, and the confidentiality of communications. For more information, see the U.S. Department of Health & Human Services website on [Health Information Privacy. ](http://www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/)

## Logs and Activity Reports

The austintexas.gov Web site collects data each time a visitor enters the austintexas.gov Web site or moves from one page to the next within the Web site. This information is used to gather statistics about visitors as a whole and in no way points to individuals. Personal information is not gathered in the austintexas.gov Web site log files. The information gathered falls into these categories.

  1. Time of day.
  2. Day of the week.
  3. Which URL was visited prior to coming to the austintexas.gov Web site.
  4. Which file you are viewing at the austintexas.gov Web site.
  5. What browser and version of browser you use.
  6. Which Operating System you use.

The above information is processed and analyzed to keep the austintexas.gov Web site up to industry standards. Portions of the Website's design and functionality are influenced by the data collected.

## Collection and Use of Information

The austintexas.gov Web site does not sell or lease personal information. Information submitted to the austintexas.gov Web site may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act. Information about the Texas Public Information Act is available from the Office of the Texas Attorney General at <http://www.oag.state.tx.us/open/requestors.shtml>.

For more information regarding specific City of Austin Connection Web pages or Web applications, contact the City of Austin’s Communications and Public Information Office at [webadmin@austintexas.gov](mailto:webadmin@austintexas.gov) or 512-974-3329.

Often personal or business information is requested by an austintexas.gov Web site online service. The request of information, storage of that information and the dissemination of that information will vary based on the department and/or service.

In each instance, clear indications of whether or not the information is required or optional will be marked.

The austintexas.gov Web site may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

## Security

This site uses a secure server for conducting online services. All credit card and other payment information that you transmit to us will be protected by 128-bit encryption technology; provided your browser is properly configured and your computer is operating properly. Security technology requires that you are using a reasonably current browser that is capable of 128-bit encryption. Current browsers provide visual cues to the visitor that the online service is secure. In the bottom of the browser you should see a key or lock. If the key is not broken or the lock is locked, then you are on a secure site. If not the site is not secure, you should not trust the transmission of personal information to the site.

Personal information is secured and only those employees that monitor the status of the computers, or perform routine maintenance are allowed access. For more information regarding the security of personal or business information, you can contact the Communications and Technology Management Department.

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are stored on the visitor's hard drive in order to place certain information regarding the transaction. A session ID, along with time date and other information may be gathered. In order for the transaction to take place, cookies must be enabled by your browser.

The austintexas.gov Web site uses cookies in some of its online services. Visitors to the Web site will be informed of when and where these cookies are present.
